aerospike.com 2019-06-21

# Privacy Policy | Aerospike

Effective date: May 25, 2018

We at Aerospike take your privacy seriously and know you care about how your personal information is used and shared. Please read the following updated Privacy Policy to learn more.

**By using or accessing the Services in any manner, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways.**

Your use of Aerospike’s Services is subject to the Terms of Use ([www.aerospike.com/forms/terms-conditions/](https://www.aerospike.com/forms/terms-conditions/)), which incorporates this Privacy Policy. Any terms we use in this Policy without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Use. 

## **What does this Privacy Policy cover** **?**

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) that we gather when you are accessing or using our Services, but not to the practices of companies we don’t own or control, or people that we don’t manage. We gather various types of Personal Information from our users, as explained in more detail below, and we use this Personal Information internally in connection with our Services, including to personalize, provide, and improve our services, to contact you and allow other users to contact you, to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, and to analyze how you use the Services. In certain cases, we may also share some Personal Information with third parties, but only as described below.

As noted in the Terms of Use, we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for the Services or send any personal information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 may have provided us personal information, please contact us at [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com).

## **Will Aerospike ever change this Privacy Policy** **?**

We’re constantly trying to improve our Services, so we may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time as well, but we will alert you to changes by placing a notice on the Aerospike Website, by sending you an email, and/or by some other means. Please note that if you’ve opted not to receive legal notice emails from us (or you haven’t provided us with your email address), those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are still responsible for reading and understanding them. If you use the Services after any changes to the Privacy Policy have been posted, you agreed to all the changes. Use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected.

## **What Information does Aerospike Collect** **?**

### Personal Information You Disclose to Aerospike

We collect personal information that you provide to us such as name, address, contact information, and social media account handles.

We collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us when registering on our Sites, expressing an interest in obtaining information about us or our products and services, when participating on the Sites (such as posting messages in our online forums) or otherwise contacting us.

The personal information that we collect depends on the context of your interactions with us and the Sites, the choices you make and the products and features you use. The personal information we collect can include the following:

  * Name and Contact Data. We collect your first and last name, email address, postal address, phone number, company, title and other similar contact data.  

### Information automatically collected

We automatically collect certain information when you visit, use or navigate the Sites. This information does not reveal your specific identity (like your name or contact information) but may include device and usage information, such as your IP address, browser and device characteristics, operating system, language preferences, referring URLs, device name, country, location, information about how and when you use our Sites and other technical information. This information is primarily needed to maintain the security and operation of our Sites, and for our internal analytics and reporting purposes.

Like many businesses, we also collect information through cookies and similar technologies.

### Information collected from other sources

We may obtain information about you from other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, social media platforms (such as Facebook, Linkedin, Github), as well as from other third parties. Examples of the information we receive from other sources include: social media profile information (your name, gender, birthday, email, current city, state and country, user identification numbers for your contacts, profile picture URL and any other information that you choose to make public) ; marketing leads and search results and links, including paid listings (such as sponsored links).

## **How do we use your information?**

We use personal information collected via our Sites for a variety of business purposes described below. We process your personal information for these purposes in reliance on our legitimate business interests (“Business Purposes”), to enter into or perform a contract with you (“Contractual”), with your consent (“Consent”), and/or for compliance with our legal obligations (“Legal Reasons”). We indicate the specific processing grounds we rely on next to each purpose listed below.

We use the information we collect or receive:

  * To send administrative information to you for Business Purposes and/or Legal Reasons. We may use your personal information to send you product, service and new feature information and/or information about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.
  * Fulfill and manage your orders for Contractual reasons. We may use your information to fulfill and manage your orders, payments, returns, and exchanges made through the Sites or direct contact with Aerospike.
  * Deliver targeted advertising to you for our Business Purposes. We may use your information to develop and display content and advertising (and work with third parties who do so) tailored to your interests and/or location and to measure its effectiveness.
  * Request Feedback for our Business Purposes. We may use your information to request feedback and to contact you about your use of our Sites.
  * To protect our Sites for Legal Reasons. We may use your information as part of our efforts to keep our Sites safe and secure (for example, for fraud monitoring and prevention).
  * To enforce our terms, conditions, and policies for Business Purposes and/or for Legal Reasons.
  * We may use your information for other Business Purposes, such as data analysis, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and to evaluate and improve our Sites, products, services, marketing, and your experience.

## **Will Aerospike Share Any of the Personal Information it Receives** **?**

We do not rent or sell your Personal Information in personally identifiable form to anyone. We may share your Personal Information with third parties as described in this section:

  * **Information that’s been de-identified.** We may de-identify your Personal Information so that you are not identified as an individual and provide that information to our partners. We may also provide aggregate usage information to our partners (or allow partners to collect that information from you), who may use such information to understand how often and in what ways people use our Services, so that they, too, can provide you with an optimal online experience. However, we never disclose aggregate usage or de-identified information to a partner (or allow a partner to collect such information) in a manner that would identify you as an individual person.
  * **Compliance with Laws.** We may disclose your information where we are legally required to do so to comply with applicable law, governmental requests, a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena (including in response to public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements).
  * **Affiliated Businesses:** In certain situations, businesses or third-party websites we’re affiliated with may sell or provide products or services to you through or in connection with the Services (either alone or jointly with us). You can recognize when an affiliated business is associated with such a transaction or service, and we will share your Personal Information with that affiliated business only to the extent that it is related to such transaction or service. We have no control over the policies and practices of third party websites or businesses as to privacy or anything else, so if you choose to take part in any transaction or service relating to an affiliated website or business, please review all such business’ or websites’ policies.
  * **Agents:** We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you; for example, we may use a payment processing company to receive and process your credit card transactions for us. Unless we tell you differently, our agents do not have any right to use the Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us.
  * **User Profiles and Submissions:** Certain user profile information, including your name, location, and any video or image content that such user has uploaded from our website, may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Services or address your request for our services. Please remember that any content you upload, along with any Personal Information or content that you voluntarily disclose online in a manner other user can view (on discussion boards, in messages and chat areas, etc.) becomes publicly available, and can be collected and used by anyone. Your username may also be displayed to other users when you send messages or comments or upload images or videos through the Services and other users can contact you through messages and comments.
  * **Business Transfers:** We may choose to buy or sell assets and may share and/or transfer customer information in connection with the evaluation of, and entry into such transactions. Also, if we (or our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, Personal Information could be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party.
  * **Protection of Aerospike and Others:** We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we [reasonably] believe is necessary to comply with law or court order; enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Aerospike, our employees, our users, or others.

## **Do we use cookies or other Tracking Technologies?**

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts are used by Aerospike and our partners (such as marketing partners), affiliates, analytics or service providers (such as online customer support providers). These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. We do link the information we store in cookies to personal information you submit while on our site.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings, for authentication and to analyze traffic patterns on our site. This can enable us over time to provide a better experience on our site by improving content or personalization and making our site easier to use. We also use cookies to facilitate shopping, personalization and registration services. For example, cookies can keep track of what you have selected to purchase as you continue to shop and allow you to enter your password only once on Web pages where a login is required. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

As is true of many websites, we gather certain information automatically with various analytical tools such as Google Analytics.  To learn more about Google Privacy and Term, [click here)](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.

We may combine this automatically collected information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, and site functionality.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites to provide you with advertising based on your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by:

  1. Selecting the e-mail “opt-out” or “unsubscribe” link or follow the opt-out instructions included in each subscription communication.
  2. Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletters and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by visiting our unsubscribe page at [www.aerospike.com/unsubscribe](http://www.aerospike.com/unsubscribe).

Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## **Is Personal Information about me secure** **?**

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect the security of any personal information we process. However, please also remember that we cannot guarantee that the internet itself is 100% secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, transmission of personal information to and from our Sites is at your own risk. You should only access the services within a secure environment.

## **How long do we keep your information?**

We will only keep your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

## **What Personal Information can I access** **?**

If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com).

California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of Personal Information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com).

## **What choices do I have** **?**

You can always opt not to disclose information to us, but keep in mind some information may be needed to register with us or to take advantage of some of our features.

If you are resident in the European Economic Area, please see below for more information about your rights.

We may also send you information about our products and services. Communications may include new product information, special offers, or an invitation to participate in market research. Out of respect for the privacy of our users, we present the option to not receive these types of communications. To be removed from our list, you can unsubscribe at [www.aerospike.com/unsubscribe](http://www.aerospike.com/unsubscribe) or email us at [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com).

You may be able to add, update, or delete information as explained above. When you update information, however, we may maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. You may request deletion of your account as follows:

To opt-out of receiving communications using any of the following methods:

  1. Select the e-mail “opt-out” or “unsubscribe” link, or follow the opt-out instructions included in each subscription communication.
  2. Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletters and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by visiting our unsubscribe page at [www.aerospike.com/unsubscribe](http://www.aerospike.com/unsubscribe).

Some information may remain in our records after your deletion of such information from your account. We may use any aggregated data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information after you update or delete it, but not in a manner that would identify you personally.

What are my rights under the GDPR?

If you are resident of the European Union (“EU”), United Kingdom, Lichtenstein, Norway, or Iceland, you may have additional rights under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”) with respect to your personal information, as outlined below.  For more information about these rights, or to submit a request, please email [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com).  Please note that in some circumstances, we may not be able to fully comply with your request, such as if it is frivolous or extremely impractical, if it jeopardizes the rights of others, or if it is not required by law, but in those circumstances, we will still respond to notify you of such a decision.  In some cases, we may also need to you to provide us with additional information, which may include personal information, if necessary to verify your identity and the nature of your request. 

  * **Access** :  You can request more information about the personal information we hold about you and request a copy of such personal information. You can also access certain of your personal information by emailing us at [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com). 
  * **Rectification** : If you believe that any personal information we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request that we correct or supplement such information. You can contact us at [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com). 
  * **Erasure** : You can request that we erase some or all of your personal information from our systems at [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com).  
  * **Withdrawal of Consent** : If we are processing your personal information based on your Consent (as indicated at the time of collection of such information), you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note, however, that if you exercise this right, you may have to then provide express consent on a case-by-case basis for the use or disclosure of certain of your personal information, if such use or disclosure is necessary to enable you to utilize some or all of our Services. 
  * **Portability** :  You can ask for a copy of your personal information in a machine-readable format.  You can also request that we transmit the data to another data controller where technically feasible.
  * **Objection** : You can contact us to let us know that you object to the further use or disclosure of your personal information for certain purposes and [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com). 
  * **Restriction of Processing** :  You can ask us to restrict further processing of your personal information.

**Right to File Complaint** :  You have the right to lodge a complaint about Aerospike’s practices with respect to your personal information with the supervisory authority of your country or EU Member State.

International Data Transfers: Privacy Shield and Contractual Terms

The Services are hosted and operated in the United States (“U.S.”) through Aerospike and its service providers, and if you do not reside in the U.S., laws in the U.S. may differ from the laws where you reside. By using the Services, you acknowledge that any personal information about you, regardless of whether provided by you or obtained from a third party, is being provided to Aerospike in the U.S. and will be hosted on U.S. servers, and you authorize Aerospike to transfer, store and process your information to and in the U.S., and possibly other countries.  You hereby consent to the transfer of your data to the U.S. pursuant to EU-U.S. or Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks, respectively, under which we are currently in the process of being certified and the details of which are further set forth below. These frameworks were developed to establish a way for companies to comply with data protection requirements when transferring personal data from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Aerospike can also enter into European Union Model Clauses, also known as Standard Contractual Clauses, to meet data transfer requirements for our customers who operate in the E.U.; please contact us at [legal@aerospike.com](mailto:legal@aerospike.com) for further information or requests to enter the Standard Contractual Clauses.

Aerospike is in the process of certifying to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework[s] set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection and use of Personal Data transferred from the EU and Switzerland to the U.S., respectively For more information about the Privacy Shield Program, please visit www.privacyshield.gov. Aerospike is committed to the Privacy Shield Principles of (1) notice, (2) consent, (3) accountability for onward transfer, (4) security, (5) data integrity and purpose limitation, (6) access and (7) recourse, enforcement and liability with respect to all Personal Data received from within the EU and Switzerland in reliance on the Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield Principles require that we remain potentially liable if any third party processing personal information on our behalf fails to comply with these Privacy Shield Principles (except to the extent we are not responsible for the event giving rise to any alleged damage).  Aerospike’s compliance with the Privacy Shield is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. 

Please contact us at [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com) with any questions or concerns relating to our Privacy Shield Certification.  If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your Privacy Shield-related complaint from us, or if we have not resolved your complaint, you may also resolve a Privacy Shield-related complaint through JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States.  You can visit [www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim](https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim) for more information or to file a complaint, at no cost to you. Under certain conditions, you may also be entitled to invoke binding arbitration for complaints not resolved by other means

## **What if I have questions about this policy?**

We are committed to privacy and security. We will remain up to date on changes to relevant privacy laws and make changes to this page accordingly.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policies, please send us a detailed message to [privacy@aerospike.com](mailto:privacy@aerospike.com) and we will try to resolve your concerns.
